<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>AllotmentAndy</title>
    <link href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/" />
    <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/feed.atom" />
    <updated>2021-03-05T14:00:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/feed.atom</id>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
                <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2021-02-21-Tailwind-CSS</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2021-02-21-Tailwind-CSS" />
    <title>Tailwind CSS</title>
    <published>2021-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">The original version of Tailwind CSS used jigsaw for the docs, the same project i use for this blog, which was lovely. However the latest version (2.0.3 at the time of writing) has migrated to next.js so it was time to investigate and install.......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>The original version of Tailwind CSS used jigsaw for the docs, the same project i use for this blog, which was lovely. However the latest version (2.0.3 at the time of writing) has migrated to next.js so it was time to investigate and install.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/tailwindlabs/tailwindcss.com">github.com/tailwindlabs/tailwindcss.com</a></p>

<p>I prefer to have apache serve all my pages locally, so i followed the instructions adding a</p>

<p><code>yarnpkg export</code></p>

<p>to create an html static site of the documentation into an 'out' directory which apache can serve, which all worked well (if a little slow to generate it all). But it all works locally, which i like.</p>

<h3>Awesome TailwindCSS</h3>

<p>As the Tailwind CSS project has grown and matured, a great <a href="https://github.com/aniftyco/awesome-tailwindcss">Awesome TailwindCSS</a> github page has grown and grown.</p>

<p>https://tail-animista.vercel.app/</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-11-15-Ansible-Ansible-Ansible-part-2</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-11-15-Ansible-Ansible-Ansible-part-2" />
    <title>Ansible Ansible Ansible - Part 2</title>
    <published>2020-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Ansible resources online, Ansible cheatsheets and Ansible Videos I really enjoyed....</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>The other day I wrote an post about the offline resources I use for learning, especially about Ansible which you can read here <a href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-11-08-Offline-documentation-on-debian" title="" target="_blank_">Offline documentation on Debian</a> Zeal and Devdocs.io are very useful.</p>

<h3>Ansible Websites and Websites</h3>

<p>I have now been using and learning Ansible for a good few months and wanted to list all the resources I regularly use.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.ansible.com/" title="" target="_blank_">www.ansible.com</a></p>

<p><a href="https://docs.ansible.com/ansible/2.9/user_guide/" title="" target="_blank_">docs.ansible.com</a></p>

<p><a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/ansible" title="" target="_blank_">Stack Overflow questions tagged with Ansible</a></p>

<h3>Ansible Videos</h3>

<p>I really like learning videos in the evening to find out more about a topic. Jeff is a great Ansible guru and this playlist has taught me a lot. His books are also superb resources for learning about the world of Ansible.</p>

<iframe id="ytplayer" type="text/html" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/goclfp6a2IQ?autoplay=0&origin=http://example.com" frameborder="0"></iframe>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-11-14-Ansible-Ansible-Ansible-part-1</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-11-14-Ansible-Ansible-Ansible-part-1" />
    <title>Ansible Ansible Ansible - Part 1</title>
    <published>2020-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">my first article in a series on Ansible, covering the Facts ansible can tell you about your machines and how I have been learning Ansible....</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Of all the Devops tools I have learnt this year, Ansible is my favourite. The ability to connect to different servers and perform different tasks in a way you can expect is superb. I have installed different flavour Linux Virtual Machines alongside my Raspberry Pi's and it connects to each one and does its thing as I expect.</p>

<p>The idea of automating everything, having it act in an expected and repeatable way is superb. I have written bash scripts that try to do this in the past, but fall over at scale and repeatability. Ansible is great for this.</p>

<p>In the process of learning ansible I have an inventory with 1 control node and 4 machines</p>

<pre><code>[x] localhost (debian 10) [Control node]
[x] virtual machine (centos 8)
[x] virtual machine (ubuntu 20)
[x] virtual machine (alpine linux 3.12)
[x] raspberry pi (raspbian)
</code></pre>

<p>With this as my personal cloud, i can connect with ansible via ssh and run a whole range of tasks including:</p>

<pre><code>[x] install and configure a webserver, mysql and install a laravel github repo
[x] run a git pull to update the repo
[x] update the OS and software
[x] install a docker container on a server 
[x] check the status of the machines 
</code></pre>

<p>Ansible provides a number of Facts for a machine which can be seen with this command:</p>

<pre><code>ansible localhost -m setup --tree /tmp/facts
</code></pre>

<p>it is a json file of around 600 lines of Facts including for my localhost machine:</p>

<pre><code>    "ansible_facts":
    {
        "ansible_os_family": "Debian",
        "ansible_architecture": "x86_64",
        "ansible_memtotal_mb": 7417,

    }
</code></pre>

<p>There is also extensive details about hardrives, IP addresses, python versions, users and the computer in general.</p>

<p>Similarly, Ansible provides details of the services running on the machine:</p>

<pre><code>ansible localhost -m service_facts --tree /tmp/services
</code></pre>

<p>it provides a 1000 line Json file, with details of the services running on the machine, here is an example of the result:</p>

<pre><code>    "ansible_facts":
    {
        "services":
            "apache2":
            {
                "name": "apache2",
                "source": "sysv",
                "state": "running"
            },
            "apache2.service":
            {
                "name": "apache2.service",
                "source": "systemd",
                "state": "running",
                "status": "enabled"
            },
    }
</code></pre>

<p>Also available is a list of package facts</p>

<pre><code>ansible localhost -m package_facts --tree /tmp/package
</code></pre>

<p>This resulted in a json file with over 20000 lines, with details of everything installed on the machine, here is a section from the result:</p>

<pre><code>    "ansible_facts":
    {
        "packages":
        {
            "apache2": [
            {
                "arch": "amd64",
                "category": "httpd",
                "name": "apache2",
                "origin": "Debian",
                "source": "apt",
                "version": "2.4.46-1"
            }],
            "zeal": [
            {
                "arch": "amd64",
                "category": "doc",
                "name": "zeal",
                "origin": "",
                "source": "apt",
                "version": "1:0.6.1-1+b1"
            }],
        }
    }
</code></pre>

<p>This provides a great deal of info about the machine, from which you could manage the the machines with conditionals like this.</p>

<pre><code>- hosts: localhost
  roles:
     - role: debian_stock_config
       when: ansible_facts['os_family'] == 'Debian'
</code></pre>

<p>One thing I really like about Ansible is it is pretty obvious what the code is doing, and logical in how it does it. All these commands in this first part are ad-hoc, as in they are single commands you run in the command line.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-11-08-Bash-fwf-ranger</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-11-08-Bash-fwf-ranger" />
    <title>Bash fwf ranger</title>
    <published>2020-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">I was recently looking for videos to help me improve my bash terminal skills and found this video by Marie-Helene Burle Fun tools to simplify your life in the command line

The two tools i really liked and have found really useful are &lt;code&gt;fzf&lt;/code&gt;......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>I was recently looking for videos to help me improve my bash terminal skills and found this video by Marie-Helene Burle <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BFKT7aj-i80" title="" target="_blank">Fun tools to simplify your life in the command line</a></p>

<p>The two tools i really liked and have found really useful are <code>fzf</code> and <code>ranger</code>.</p>

<h3>fzf</h3>

<p>fzf is a fuzzy search for the terminal. To search for docs in the directory which contain ansible  run <code>ls | fzf</code> and i can type ansible and it shows the files that contain ansible.</p>

<p>To search for ansible only use:</p>

<pre><code>ls | fzf -e -q "ansible"
</code></pre>

<h3>ranger</h3>

<p><code>ranger</code> is a terminal file manager that is nice and quick and lets me navigate and view the file content.</p>

<p>both of these tools can be installed with</p>

<pre><code>apt-get install fzf ranger
</code></pre>

<p>I am always on the lookout for more tools that improve and speed up the workflow.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-11-08-Offline-documentation-on-debian</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-11-08-Offline-documentation-on-debian" />
    <title>Offline Documentation on Debian</title>
    <published>2020-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">A lot of the time I work offline, learning, reading, watching and playing to learn more and more.

One thing i really like to use is offline tools to help me access info offline. However I am looking for info on a wide range of topics including devops,......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>A lot of the time I work offline, learning, reading, watching and playing to learn more and more.</p>

<p>One thing i really like to use is offline tools to help me access info offline. However I am looking for info on a wide range of topics including devops, webdev, frontend, backend and linux in general. There is no one super tool which covers everything so here is a list of my favourite souces.</p>

<h3>man</h3>

<p>The <code>man</code> command provides a great starting point to read the manpages for a command. eg. <code>man ansible</code> gives a good intro, but it isnt the most readable or user friendly.</p>

<h3>apropos</h3>

<p>Finding what <code>man apropos</code> pages are available is possible with <code>apropos ansible</code></p>

<h3>gman</h3>

<p>Alongside the command line tools above, <code>gman</code> is a neat GUI tool to show an index of the man pages on the system.</p>

<h3>tldr</h3>

<p>tldr is similar to the man pages above, but gives examples of usage. <code>tldr git</code> or <code>tldr ansible</code> all provide a neat list of the most common commands you want to use. You have to update the database of info with the <code>tldr --update</code> command</p>

<h3>eg</h3>

<p>In a similar vain to tldr above, eg, provides even more examples of how to use a command, with a bit more detail.</p>

<h3>Zeal</h3>

<p>Zeal is a GUI which allows one to download docs to read offline. It doesnt cover as much, for example it has the docs for Ansible, Docker and Laravel, but not Terraform</p>

<h3>devdocs.io</h3>

<p>devdocs.io is an offline website which allows you to download the docs to read offline. It does cover Terraform, Ansible, Laravel and more. I use it with Chrome with a plugin</p>

<hr />

<p>I would be interested in anymore tools people use for offline documentation, especially one that covers Tailwind CSS.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-08-25-bash-scripts-for-laravel-php-linux-devops</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-08-25-bash-scripts-for-laravel-php-linux-devops" />
    <title>Bash Scripts for Laravel PHP Linux Devops</title>
    <published>2020-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Having spent the summer learning more of the Devops toolkit, I often come back to bash shell scripts to achieve something.



I wanted a little script to import the values of the .env file to use in the bash scripts. This works as i expect.





This is......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Having spent the summer learning more of the Devops toolkit, I often come back to bash shell scripts to achieve something.</p>

<h3>importEnv.sh</h3>

<p>I wanted a little script to import the values of the .env file to use in the bash scripts. This works as i expect.</p>

<pre><code class="language-bash">#!/bin/bash

source /var/www/laravel/.env
echo $DB_USERNAME
</code></pre>

<h3>mysqlBackup</h3>

<p>This is a one liner to backup all the mysql databases.</p>

<pre><code>mysql -u root -p -N -e 'show databases' | while read dbname; do mysqldump -u root -p --complete-insert --routines --triggers --single-transaction "$dbname" &gt; "$dbname".sql; done

</code></pre>

<h3>deploy.sh</h3>

<p>Working with the jigsaw static site builder, i wrote this simple script to copy the production version of the site to another directory and deploy it to the github pages site.</p>

<pre><code class="language-bash">#!/bin/bash -e

echo "Deploying build_production to allotmentandy.github.io"
echo "---------"

cd build_production 
cp -r * /var/www/allotmentandy.github.io

cd /var/www/allotmentandy.github.io

git add .
git commit -m "update"
git push

echo 'finished'
</code></pre>

<h3>clearLaravelCaches.sh</h3>

<pre><code class="language-bash">#!/bin/bash

echo "This a bash script to run composer clear the caches)"
echo "--------------"
php -v
#echo "--------------"

cd /var/www/laravel

php artisan down

composer dump-autoload -o

php artisan view:clear
php artisan config:clear
php artisan cache:clear
php artisan route:clear
php artisan clear-compiled
php artisan config:cache
php artisan optimize

php artisan up
</code></pre>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-07-27-moving-into-devops</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-07-27-moving-into-devops" />
    <title>Moving into Devops</title>
    <published>2020-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">In my last contract role, I spent more time working with the Devops team than the frontend team. I really enjoyed it and now feel that this is a better path for me. I have been using the command line to build, manage and test servers for many many years......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>In my last contract role, I spent more time working with the Devops team than the frontend team. I really enjoyed it and now feel that this is a better path for me. I have been using the command line to build, manage and test servers for many many years and feel this is somewhere I can offer more to companies in the future.</p>

<p>I was on twitter and I found this article <a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/alternative-career-paths/">about alternative career paths from freecodecamp</a> and the Devops idea was one most appealing to me.</p>

<p>I have spent a lot of the last few months learning more and more about linux and the Command line. Including learning Bash Scripting and Python.</p>

<h3>ssh</h3>

<p>create a ssh key and copy it to the raspberry pi:</p>

<pre><code>root@linuxtechi:~# ssh-keygen
root@linuxtechi:~# ssh-copy-id root@192.168.1.156
</code></pre>

<p>This allows you to ssh into the machine without a password.</p>

<h3>Bash Cheat sheet</h3>

<p>Back in the days as an Apple Mac user, i really like Applescript. With these little scripts you could get stuff done quickly and easily. Laravel also provides a need way to write command line scripts which allow me to download and process the data.</p>

<p>Bash scripting is similar, i now have scripts to create new posts for this blog, build the css/js with webpack, deploy the site to github and many more.</p>

<p>To help, I have added a <a href="/bash_shortcuts">Bash Cheat cheet</a> to this blog.</p>

<h3>Ansible</h3>

<p>Ansible is a tool to software provisioning, configuration management, and application-deployment tool. <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ansible_(software)">wikipedia</a></p>

<p><a href="https://opensource.com/resources/what-ansible">opensource.com intro to ansible</a></p>

<p>I do like learning from videos and I found this series of videos 
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL2_OBreMn7FplshFCWYlaN2uS8et9RjNG">Ansible with Jeff Geerling</a></p>

<p>Cheatsheets</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/germainlefebvre4/ansible-cheatsheet">github.com/germainlefebvre4/ansible-cheatsheet</a></p>

<p><a href="https://armoucar.github.io/ansible-cheatsheet/">armoucar.github.io/ansible-cheatsheet/</a></p>

<p>Now i can setup a hosts file like so:</p>

<pre><code>[raspberrypi]
192.168.1.166 ansible_ssh_user=pi hostname=raspberrypi

</code></pre>

<p>Once i set up the ssh login (see above), i can now test the server connection with</p>

<pre><code>ansible -i hosts -m ping raspberrypi
</code></pre>

<p>i have setup a new github repo which i run like this:</p>

<pre><code>ansible-playbook site.yml -i hosts
</code></pre>

<h3>Vagrant and Virtualbox</h3>

<p>With Laravel there is Homestead which provides an easy vagrant box with all the linux tools to run a website. I have also used Virtualbox for years to run debian boxes from around the time of Debian 6.</p>

<pre><code>vagrant up
vagrant halt
vagrant ssh
</code></pre>

<h3>Docker</h3>

<p>Docker takes the whole Vagrant VM forward and makes an entire container which you can deploy as the finished website. I have used it before in my last contract role and found it very powerful.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BvDXzyOP3NE">Kickass Laravel Development with Docker - David McKay - Laracon EU 2018 Amsterdam</a></p>

<h3>Jenkins</h3>

<p>Jenkins is a Continuous Integration and testing environment which allows you to test your code as it is pushed to Github.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kuBD3p20oyE">PHP UK Conference 2018 - Michael Heap - Zero to Jenkins: Automatic builds + deploys
</a></p>

<p>I am installing Jenkins on my Raspberry Pi using this tutorial from 
<a href="https://pimylifeup.com/jenkins-raspberry-pi/">https://pimylifeup.com/jenkins-raspberry-pi/</a></p>

<p><a href="http://jenkins-php.org/installation.html">jenkins-php.org</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/amochohan/laravel-jenkins-ci-boilerplate">https://github.com/amochohan/laravel-jenkins-ci-boilerplate</a></p>

<p>To install jenkins add this to the playbook</p>

<pre><code>   tasks:
    - name: ensure the jenkins apt repository key is installed
      apt_key: url=https://pkg.jenkins.io/debian-stable/jenkins.io.key state=present
      become: yes

    - name: ensure the repository is configured
      apt_repository: repo='deb https://pkg.jenkins.io/debian-stable binary/' state=present
      become: yes

    - name: ensure jenkins is installed
      apt: name=jenkins update_cache=yes
      become: yes

    - name: ensure jenkins is running
      service: name=jenkins state=started
</code></pre>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-07-16-general-thoughts</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-07-16-general-thoughts" />
    <title>General Thoughts about getting some work.</title>
    <published>2020-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">I have been trying to get some work, so I tried nextdoor.co.uk and upwork.com, here is how it went....</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>I have been trying a number of new things to try and get work.</p>

<p>Firstly i discovered <a href="http://www.nextdoor.co.uk">nextdoor.co.uk</a> a localised website for helping people communicate with each other. The site excited me at first and I managed to post a number of messages about potential jobs/work. The first one about IT work got one response, I elderly gentleman who wanted help 'in the future' with setting up a laptop, security and more. However, he has never got back to me and I dont hold out much hope that he will. The second post was offering gardening work, something I can do and enjoy. This too had one response, from a lady nearby. I wondered round, to find a tiny garden, but alas the women had no money to pay for the work and was just trying to get me to do it as a portfolio piece. Hmm. Further posts have gotten me nowhere except I guy that asked for a day or twos labour, and then cancelled the day before as his cousin was coming and would do it for free. Great.</p>

<p>Yesterday, I emailed / contacted around 10 local gardening firms about gardening work and have got zero replies. Great.</p>

<p>Yesterday I also looked at finding potential work on <a href="https://www.upwork.com">Upwork.com</a> A website for freelancers and companies to content for work. I have used this website before and also elance which they have taken over in the past. I preferred elance as it worked better without all the fancy javascript which doesn't quite work. Now though, Upwork has created a type of currency called 'connects' which you have to buy for the right to connect with potential jobs. I have used this site to hire programmers in the past, and the spam was very high.</p>

<p>So still trying to find work, any ideas?</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-06-25-laravel-starter-projects</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-06-25-laravel-starter-projects" />
    <title>Laravel starter projects</title>
    <published>2020-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Looking at Laravel starter projects which offer more than a basic install including an admin system, login and more....</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Yesterday i wrote about how i was looking at wordpress and laravel starter projects to build a website directory. I installed a number of wordpress projects but non of them seemed to be what I am looking for.</p>

<p>So I started to look for a Laravel starter project that i can work with.</p>

<p>I am going to install each one and write a blog on the experience of each.</p>

<h4>https://github.com/laravel-frontend-presets/tailwindcss</h4>

<p>I was looking for something simple with just tailwind and laravel so i also found this:</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/laravel-frontend-presets/tailwindcss">laravel frontend presets / tailwindcss</a></p>

<p>You start with a default laravel install and justs add the presets on top.</p>

<h4>Jeremy Kenedy / laravel-auth</h4>

<p>I have used this project in the past and found it great.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/jeremykenedy/laravel-auth" title="" target="_blank">laravel-auth</a></p>

<h4>innocenzi / laravel-boilerplate</h4>

<p><a href="https://github.com/innocenzi/laravel-boilerplate" title="" target="_blank">laravel-boilerplate</a></p>

<h4>nasirkhan / laravel-starter</h4>

<p><a href="https://github.com/nasirkhan/laravel-starter" title="" target="_blank">nasirkhan/laravel-starter</a></p>

<h4>rappasoft / Laravel Boilerplate</h4>

<p><a href="https://github.com/rappasoft/laravel-boilerplate">Laravel Boilerplate</a></p>

<h4>laraship-laravel-directory</h4>

<p><a href="https://www.laraship.com/product/laraship-laravel-directory/" title="" target="_blank">laraship laravel directory</a></p>

<p>Not really a starter project, more of a solution of what i am trying to offer.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-07-04-pdf-making-pdfs-extracting-pages-from-pdfs</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-07-04-pdf-making-pdfs-extracting-pages-from-pdfs" />
    <title>Playing with PDFs</title>
    <published>2020-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">I have always loved reading, on my computer, phone, books, magazines and newspapers. I have collected a huge number of PDFs over the years. Here is how i work with them....</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-06-25-getting-your-github-pages-sites-into-google</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-06-25-getting-your-github-pages-sites-into-google" />
    <title>Getting your Github Pages site into Google</title>
    <published>2020-06-25T20:52:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-25T20:52:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">How I got Google to index / crawl my site by submitting it via the Google Search Console....</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>I have been running this website for a few months and what started as an experiment I am rather enjoying as a place to write and play around with Code and more.</p>

<p>But one thing I checked yesterday, was how many pages were indexed by Google.</p>

<p>Google search for "site:http://allotmentandy.github.io/" and the answer was NONE - ZERO - ZILCH - NADA!!</p>

<p>But Google provided a handy link to its Google Search Console. So i managed to login to my Google account, added a meta tag to the layout template and managed to get Google to index the site. Today there are 8 pages in the Google index. Which is better.</p>

<p>Small wins each day! Of those 8 pages, 3 only have 'AllotmentAndy' as the title, The blog index page has 'AllotmentAndy - GitHub Pages' as the title and the others have 'AllotmentAndy - PAGE TITLE'</p>

<p>Will see how this changes over the next few days.</p>

<p>Would like to improve the Title tags for the static pages in the root. I have added some yaml to the top of the web safe fonts page to improve the title tag. Lets see how long it takes Google to notice!</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-06-24-relaunching-my-directory</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-06-24-relaunching-my-directory" />
    <title>Relaunching my directory</title>
    <published>2020-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Back in 1998, i registered a url, londinium.com and built a website directory. Over the years, i built quite a nice website, with over 100,000 links to mainly London based information. However in 2015, it started to be bought down daily by DDOS attacks.......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <h3>Directory websites in Wordpress</h3>

<p>Back in 1998, i registered a url, londinium.com and built a website directory. Over the years, i built quite a nice website, with over 100,000 links to mainly London based information. However in 2015, it started to be bought down daily by DDOS attacks. It was also removed from google searches and the revenue went down towards zero. So i shut it down.</p>

<p>Since then, i have tried with a shopify online store, but that hasnt worked.</p>

<p>So i come back to the idea of a London directory website, but want to make it more useful.</p>

<p>So i am going to look at Wordpress plugins to re-launch londinium.</p>

<p>These are the wordpress directories i have looked at, to be far i wasnt too impressed with any of them.</p>

<h2>Wordpress Directories Plugins</h2>

<h4>Geo-directory</h4>

<p><a href="https://wpgeodirectory.com/" title="" target="_blank">Geo-directory</a><br />
<a href="https://wordpress.org/plugins/geodirectory/" title="" target="_blank">Geo-directory on Wordpress</a></p>

<h4>Business Directory</h4>

<p><a href="https://businessdirectoryplugin.com/" title="" target="_blank">Business Directory</a><br />
<a href="https://wordpress.org/plugins/business-directory-plugin/" title="" target="_blank">Business Directory on Wordpress</a></p>

<h4>Advanced Classifieds &amp; Directory Pro</h4>

<p><a href="https://pluginsware.com/" title="" target="_blank">Pluginsware</a><br />
<a href="https://wordpress.org/plugins/advanced-classifieds-and-directory-pro/" title="" target="_blank">Advanced Classifieds &amp; Directory Pro on Wordpress</a></p>

<h4>Hivepress</h4>

<p>This looked the most impressive on first glimpse, but the demo content wouldnt import and after a few tries i gave up.</p>

<p><a href="https://hivepress.io/" title="" target="_blank">Hivepress</a><br />
<a href="https://wordpress.org/plugins/hivepress/" title="" target="_blank">Hivepress on Wordpress</a></p>

<h4>Web Directory Free</h4>

<p><a href="https://www.salephpscripts.com/wordpress_directory/demo/" title="" target="_blank">Web Directory Free</a><br />
<a href="[https://wordpress.org/plugins/web-directory-free/]" title="" target="_blank">Web Directory Free on Wordpress</a></p>

<p>I would be interested in seeing websites that use any of these plugins and chat to users of these plugins, but it looks like I am going to have to build something myself.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-06-06-rss-feeds-debian</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-06-06-rss-feeds-debian" />
    <title>RSS Feeds with Debian Linux</title>
    <published>2020-06-06T10:29:57+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-06T10:29:57+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">I have always been a fan of RSS feeds going back years. In case you don&#039;t know, RSS feeds (and ATOM feeds) are text files that provide the latest pages from a website. I use them for News, website statuses and more.

I use a number of RSS feed readers on......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>I have always been a fan of RSS feeds going back years. In case you don't know, RSS feeds (and ATOM feeds) are text files that provide the latest pages from a website. I use them for News, website statuses and more.</p>

<p>I use a number of RSS feed readers on my Debian machine and wanted to highlight what I like about each one.</p>

<h3>QuiteRSS</h3>

<p>My main RSS feed reader, i like it, but it is a little slow to open and close. One small problem I have is that when i open it, it is always set to "ALWAYS ON TOP". Everytime I open QuiteRSS, i have to untick the "ALWAYS ON TOP" setting in the right click. I cannot find how this has been set in the settings/options panels. Maybe this is a feature I discovered in another window manager, as i used LXDE earlier. Any ideas how to unset this?</p>

<p>All round, i like QuiteRSS, it doesnt have a progress box to show downloads, something I would like to see as i often work with sporadic internet connections.</p>

<p>There is an ability to search within one feed, but thats not how I need to search.</p>

<p>One really annoying feature is if you click on the line between the news items in a feed, it decides to open in a browser. This also tends to open a new browser window, but as i am offline, it just gives an error page.</p>

<p>Another strange feature is that many articles are marked as read, even thou i havent had a chance to read the feeds. I tend to go to the wireless hotspot, download all the feeds and go back to my desk to read them. But they are often marked read.</p>

<p>I use QuiteRSS as my main feed reader, but am open to new ways. So i tried the following apps, but none quite did it for me!</p>

<h3>Liferea</h3>

<p>I like the way you can read the unread feeds across all the feeds in the app. This is how i have gone through the feeds, but it is a little unnerving when they disappear after you click on the next one. But i suppose this is now not unread!</p>

<p>I also liked the way there was a make folder option, QuiteRSS doesnt offer folders for the feeds, so they are all in one long list. The problem with Liferea is that any folder I make, doesn't actually appear.</p>

<h3>Akregator</h3>

<p>After finding a number of OPML files (rss backups) on github, I wanted to see what these feeds offered, but didnt want to clog up QuiteRSS or Liferea with other peoples feeds, so i used Akregator.</p>

<p>Akregator was quite minimal, but let me import 5 opml files with ease and read the feeds.</p>

<p>However, after shutting down Akregator (or so i thought) It seems to keep a background process running which created errors as i am offline a lot.</p>

<p>So now i dont use Akregator much as that background process wasnt what i wanted.</p>

<h3>Newsboat</h3>

<p>I installed a Command Line (CLI) to test out what RSS feeds were like from the command line. I imported my main opml file to give it a whirl, but on reopening the app after the first feed update, all the feeds were gone. So i gave up on that one.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>I would be interested in any solutions to issues i have written about here. You can contact me via <a href="https://www.github.com/allotmentandy1">twitter</a>
If you can share your feeds via .OPML files I would love to see what you read.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-06-05-looking-for-work</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-06-05-looking-for-work" />
    <title>Looking for work</title>
    <published>2020-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">I am looking for work in London or remotely. I have years of experience in web development, web design and in IT in general. Also available in West London on an hourly basis to help you fix your IT problems, like wifi, virus removal, updates, installation and more......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-30-testing</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-30-testing" />
    <title>Testing</title>
    <published>2020-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">There was a website a long time ago called the World Question Centre, where they asked famous people to ask one question. One of the respondents asked Why is music such a pleasure? I always loved this questions as I see it as perfect.

I have also used......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <h3>Why is music such a pleasure?</h3>

<p>There was a website a long time ago called the World Question Centre, where they asked famous people to ask one question. One of the respondents asked <em>Why is music such a pleasure?</em> I always loved this questions as I see it as perfect.</p>

<p>I have also used this question to test people. If I say this to you and you try to answer it, you have missed the point. The answer isnt in something in the ears and brain or any other reason. It is just a great question, it is not a test to answer. I am looking for people who say, <em>What a great question</em>.</p>

<p>IBM used to test people like this, if you were looking for work at IBM, they would take you to dinner to sillently test you. Once you got your food, if you put salt and pepper on before tasting it, you failed! They are looking for people who fit a high quality culture. I notice people putting on salt and pepper often and think of this.</p>

<p>There are a number of other questions i like to ask to test people and see what they are made of. For example, another question is, <em>Where does money come from, how is it made?</em></p>

<p>This sort of testing people is to route out people who do not think and just live in a bubble of ignorance. I am not trying to say I am right here, just it is a waste of time to engage with people who cannot question what they think they know. How can these help you improve if they do not improve themselves.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-23-idea-days-work-days</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-23-idea-days-work-days" />
    <title>Idea Days Work Days</title>
    <published>2020-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Some days I can be really creative, other days I am to be really productive. It&#039;s a nice mix as one has to work out what to do, then do it. I like to experiment a lot, so there is a lot of research one can do.

Today I started an article on RSS viewers......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Some days I can be really creative, other days I am to be really productive. It's a nice mix as one has to work out what to do, then do it. I like to experiment a lot, so there is a lot of research one can do.</p>

<p>Today I started an article on RSS viewers that are easy to install with Debian. I found a cool command line app called newsboat, which i have been using today.</p>

<p>On a personal note, i was given a nickname last year, WOODY, which was the name of the 3rd version of Debian! Lovely...</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-17-tailwind-css</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-17-tailwind-css" />
    <title>Tailwind CSS</title>
    <published>2020-05-17T11:42:57+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-17T11:42:57+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">One thing i really liked about this Jigsaw static site generator is it comes with Tailwind Css and a working Laravel Mix / Webpack / PurgeCSS solution.

Tailwind CSS is much more like coding CSS / HTML about 20 years ago. But the difference being you can......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>One thing i really liked about this Jigsaw static site generator is it comes with Tailwind Css and a working Laravel Mix / Webpack / PurgeCSS solution.</p>

<p>Tailwind CSS is much more like coding CSS / HTML about 20 years ago. But the difference being you can do soo much with a core set of standard css options.</p>

<p>The advantage is that you just write the html with classes that make sense to the context of what you are doing with the html element.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-17-my-newPost-bash-script</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-17-my-newPost-bash-script" />
    <title>My New Post Bash Shell Script</title>
    <published>2020-05-17T10:46:57+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-17T10:46:57+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">I like to make shell scripts to make my life easier. this is my current newPost script. It isnt very comlicated, but gives me a simple blank post, quickly.

I would like it to format the $something in camel case with the dashs removed by spaces.

Also, I......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>I like to make shell scripts to make my life easier. this is my current newPost script. It isnt very comlicated, but gives me a simple blank post, quickly.</p>

<p>I would like it to format the $something in camel case with the dashs removed by spaces.</p>

<p>Also, I could add a line to open it in sublime</p>

<pre><code class="language-bash">#!/bin/bash

echo -n "New File Name:"
read something

echo "You Entered: $something"

FILE="source/_posts/$(date +%F)-$something.md"

touch $FILE

cat &gt; $FILE &lt;&lt; EOF
---
extends: _layouts.post
section: content
title: $something
date: $(date +%F)
description: 
cover_image: 
excerpt: 
categories: []
---
EOF

</code></pre>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-17-highlight-js</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-17-highlight-js" />
    <title>Using highlight.js</title>
    <published>2020-05-17T02:02:02+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-17T02:02:02+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Jigsaw comes with highlightjs to show code blocks in colour, here is a CSS, HTML and Bash output for the jigsaw command...</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Jigsaw comes with highlightjs to show code blocks in colour, here is a CSS, HTML and Bash output for the jigsaw command</p>

<h3>CSS</h3>

<pre><code class="language-css"><br />{
    body: 
}

</code></pre>

<h3>HTML</h3>

<pre><code class="language-html"><br />&lt;a href='#'&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;

</code></pre>

<h3>bash ./vendor/bin/jigsaw</h3>

<pre><code class="language-bash">Jigsaw 1.3.27

Usage:
  command [options] [arguments]

Options:
  -h, --help            Display this help message
  -q, --quiet           Do not output any message
  -V, --version         Display this application version
      --ansi            Force ANSI output
      --no-ansi         Disable ANSI output
  -n, --no-interaction  Do not ask any interactive question
  -v|vv|vvv, --verbose  Increase the verbosity of messages: 1 for normal output, 2 for more verbose output and 3 for debug

Available commands:
  build  Build your site.
  help   Displays help for a command
  init   Scaffold a new Jigsaw project.
  list   Lists commands
  serve  Serve local site with php built-in server.

</code></pre>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-17-blade</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-17-blade" />
    <title>Testing a blade.md template for a post</title>
    <published>2020-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Trying to get a blade.md template to work as i expect....</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-17-internationalization_of_this_jigsaw_static_site</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-17-internationalization_of_this_jigsaw_static_site" />
    <title>Internationalization Of A Jigsaw Static Site</title>
    <published>2020-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Alongside playing with code, i like to learn Portuguese. So i was wondering this morning the best way to make a Portuguese version of the site.

I would like a language switcher to swap between EN and PT at first. This would change the nav, footer and......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Alongside playing with code, i like to learn Portuguese. So i was wondering this morning the best way to make a Portuguese version of the site.</p>

<p>I would like a language switcher to swap between EN and PT at first. This would change the nav, footer and buttons across the site. Perhaps there could be a posts_pt directory for tranlsated posts, which i would like to have auto-translated by some online gizmo (google)?</p>

<p>I wonder if this the way others have tackled this problem in the past.</p>

<p>Can javascript detect the locale? i need to search this next.</p>

<p>I have created an <a href="/about-pt/">/about_pt</a> page to experiment with this</p>

<p>https://lokalise.com/blog/localizing-apps-jquery/</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-13-jigsaw-experiment</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-13-jigsaw-experiment" />
    <title>Jigsaw experiment with ~20,000 pages</title>
    <published>2020-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">I wanted to try and experiment to see how many pages i can make in jigsaw, how long it would take to build and also would the search take it.

My idea is to output markdown pages for the 20,000 private jets in my laravel54 package. i think it will be......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>I wanted to try and experiment to see how many pages i can make in jigsaw, how long it would take to build and also would the search take it.</p>

<p>My idea is to output markdown pages for the 20,000 private jets in my laravel54 package. i think it will be easiest to make a laravel command to output it, then copy them to the jigsaw _posts directory to build.</p>

<p>Will it be able to handle it?</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-09-jigsaw-ideas</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-09-jigsaw-ideas" />
    <title>Jigsaw Ideas</title>
    <published>2020-05-09T14:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-09T14:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">I am still enjoying jigsaw and have a couple of ideas to improve my site with it.



I really like the search provided out of the box with the jigsaw blog template. but I want to add the about page to the search.

The collection in the config.php file......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>I am still enjoying jigsaw and have a couple of ideas to improve my site with it.</p>

<h3>Adding about page to the search json</h3>

<p>I really like the search provided out of the box with the jigsaw blog template. but I want to add the about page to the search.</p>

<p>The collection in the config.php file needs to have the about page added.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-09-yesterday-i-cooked</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-09-yesterday-i-cooked" />
    <title>Yesterday I Cooked</title>
    <published>2020-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Yesterday it was my turn to cook. I made a Focaccia. for lunch, a  2 pound loaf and a lemon maderia cake.

lunch was a smorgasbord of fresh salad with the nice focaccia.

Dinner was a large stir-fry of the first pak choi leaves with kale, chinese cabbage......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Yesterday it was my turn to cook. I made a Focaccia. for lunch, a  2 pound loaf and a lemon maderia cake.</p>

<p>lunch was a smorgasbord of fresh salad with the nice focaccia.</p>

<p>Dinner was a large stir-fry of the first pak choi leaves with kale, chinese cabbage and mizuna.</p>

<p>It was all very nice</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-09-grr-duplicate-github-pages</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-09-grr-duplicate-github-pages" />
    <title>GRR, Duplicate Github Pages</title>
    <published>2020-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">12.26pm

It took me all morning to fix this website deploy issue, there was an old old repo that was setup years ago as an experiment.

I deleted that repo and now it is working as expected....</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>12.26pm</p>

<p>It took me all morning to fix this website deploy issue, there was an old old repo that was setup years ago as an experiment.</p>

<p>I deleted that repo and now it is working as expected.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-04-30-laravel</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-04-30-laravel" />
    <title>Laravel</title>
    <published>2020-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Laravel is a great PHP Framework which i have used for many years.

There are a number of Laravel projects I am enjoying using at the moment

Laravel Boilerplate

Laravel Auth

I am looking to create a dual language website in English and Portuguese to......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Laravel is a great PHP Framework which i have used for many years.</p>

<p>There are a number of Laravel projects I am enjoying using at the moment</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/rappasoft/laravel-boilerplate">Laravel Boilerplate</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/jeremykenedy/laravel-auth/">Laravel Auth</a></p>

<p>I am looking to create a dual language website in English and Portuguese to help me learn portuguese and as a playground to learn about internationalization and multi-language websites.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-08-markdown</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-05-08-markdown" />
    <title>Markdown</title>
    <published>2020-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">A list of examples of markdown in action...</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Markdown</p>

<p><a href="https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax">Daring Fireball</a> The most comprehensive guide to markdown I have seen</p>

<p><a href="https://michelf.ca/projects/php-markdown/extra/#spe-attr">markdown extra</a></p>

<pre><code class="language-markdown"># Markdown syntax

https://guides.github.com/features/mastering-markdown/

**bold**

*italic*

Hello there `people`, how are you?

![Image of Angular](https://www.w3schools.com/angular/pic_angular.jpg)

[link to Google!](http://google.com)

&gt; Hello there people
&gt; How are you?

- [x] This is a complete item
- [ ] This is an incomplete item

Hello @damusix this is just some markdown examples!

emojis :sparkles: :camel: :boom:

https://www.webpagefx.com/tools/emoji-cheat-sheet/



# This is an `&lt;h1&gt;` tag
## This is an `&lt;h2&gt;` tag
###### This is an `&lt;h6&gt;` tag



*This text will be italic*
_This will also be italic_


**This text will be bold**
__This will also be bold__


_You **can** combine them_

###### Lists

* Item 1
* Item 2
  * Item 2a
  * Item 2b


1. Item 1
1. Item 2
1. Item 3
   1. Item 3a
   1. Item 3b


![An Image from this repo](/images/logo.png)
Format: ![Alt Text](url)


http://github.com - automatic!
[GitHub](http://github.com)





###### Checklists

- [x] @mentions, #refs, [links](google.com), **formatting**, and &lt;del&gt;del tags&lt;/del&gt; supported
- [x] list syntax required (any unordered or ordered list supported)
- [x] this is a complete item
- [ ] this is an incomplete item


###### Tables

First Header | Second Header
------------ | -------------
Content from cell 1 | Content from cell 2
Content in the first column | Content in the second column





Any URL (like http://www.github.com/) will be automatically converted into a clickable link.

Any word wrapped with two tildes (like ~~this~~) will appear crossed out.



###### numbered lists:

1. One
2. Two
3. Three

###### bullet points:

* Start a line with a star
* Profit!

###### dashes for lists

- Dashes work just as well
- And if you have sub points, put two spaces before the dash or star:
  - Like this
  - And this
</code></pre>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-04-30</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-04-30" />
    <title>Cooking Day</title>
    <published>2020-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Yesterday i made a tray of yeast following this recipe
WikiHow

This create 27 yeast blocks of around 0.6 ounces each. I left these drying
overnight and today i will make bread and freeze a load of these....</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Yesterday i made a tray of yeast following this recipe
<a href="https://www.wikihow.com/Create-Yeast-for-Baking">WikiHow</a></p>

<p>This create 27 yeast blocks of around 0.6 ounces each. I left these drying
overnight and today i will make bread and freeze a load of these.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-04-29</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-04-29" />
    <title>Jigsaw Templates</title>
    <published>2020-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Working on templates for this static site. The mix of markdown and HTML isnt
working.



[ ] Daily page - template for each day, with a shell script to create it

[ ] Code page - with examples of code blocks

[ ] Markdown Examples



[x] Build.sh - build......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <h3>7.35 am</h3>

<p>Working on templates for this static site. The mix of markdown and HTML isnt
working.</p>

<h4>Templates to make</h4>

<p>[ ] Daily page - template for each day, with a shell script to create it</p>

<p>[ ] Code page - with examples of code blocks</p>

<p>[ ] Markdown Examples</p>

<h4>Shell Scripts</h4>

<p>[x] Build.sh - build both the local and production sites</p>

<p>[ ] Deploy to github.io</p>

<p>[ ] Create daily post page</p>

<p><a href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/">AllotmentAndy.github.io</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.github.com/allotmentandy">AllotmentAndy at Github</a></p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-04-29-jigsaw-static-site-thoughts</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-04-29-jigsaw-static-site-thoughts" />
    <title>Jigsaw Static Site Thoughts</title>
    <published>2020-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">I was looking for a project to help me do a few things. write a blog, store
reference material for things I am interested in, create a database of plants
I like to grow, learn about markdown &amp;amp; JSON and also expand my use of shell
scripts.

Having......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>I was looking for a project to help me do a few things. write a blog, store
reference material for things I am interested in, create a database of plants
I like to grow, learn about markdown &amp; JSON and also expand my use of shell
scripts.</p>

<p>Having been online for 25 years, I have gone from an all rounder managing CSS,
graphics, code and servers back to being an all rounder doing the same thing.
In the intervening years, I have worked with PHP, Codeigniter and now mainly
Laravel and have set up this system to allow me to entertain myself whilst
(re)learning CSS, Javascript, Markdown, JSON, Bash Scripting and Graphic
Design, something I have ignore for too long.</p>

<p>Having moved to using Debian Linux as my main daily machine, I have enjoyed
setting up a number of projects but wanted somewhere to combine and publish my
writing and experiments for all to see.</p>

<p>So although I had known about Jigsaw for years as a Laravel developer, i
recently took the plunge and installed it. I have tried a number of other
static site generators including Hugo and Jekyll but they didn't really click
with me for a number of reasons. Although I have 'played' with Ruby, Go and
Python, I tend to fall back to bash and PHP as the languages i like. I also
wanted something that wasn't huge, but powerful enough for me get stuff done
without a huge learning curve.</p>

<p>So Jigsaw uses the Laravel Blade syntax that I have used in many other
projects and comes with a neat quick start blog with a nifty search facility
from fuse.js which uses json. I created a site with a blog (_posts) and static
pages (_pages), but the search facility only indexed the blog. No problem, i
created a new collection in the generateIndex handle method and merged the 2
collections, then hey presto, it worked.</p>

<p>There are a number of features I liked 'out of the box' there was a RSS/ATOM
feed included. This is great as I am a big fan of the RSS feed concept.</p>

<p>The basic app also had a category system which I have included via an
autogenerated collection in the config file.</p>

<p>The Jigsaw blog system also uses Tailwind CSS, Webpack and Laravel Mix to
process the CSS and Js with the <code>npm run dev</code> and <code>npm run production</code>
commands.</p>

<p>I have really quite enjoyed the experience and will publish this all on
github.io and github.com/allotmentandy in the near future. Enjoying working
with CSS and next for the imagery.</p>

<p>Playing with the SVG image format is also on the to-do list.</p>

<h4>Observations</h4>

<p>[ ] fuse.js search json generator only takes the first 255 chars of the page
content.</p>

<p>[ ] the build process is very fast, taking about 0.2 seconds to build the
site.</p>

<p>[ ] Tailwind CSS is really nice once you get your head around it, it is like
CSS used to be.</p>

<p>[ ] I miss the 'php artisan' commands, i want a script to create a blog page
for today, with the date and time now, the filename i give it and a basic div.
like this <code>php artisan make:post 'title of post'</code> but i will make it in bash</p>

<p><a href="http://localhost:3000/blog/2020-04-29" title="Older Post: Templates, Markdown and
Shell Scripts for Jigsaw">  Templates, Markdown and Shell Scripts for Jigsaw
</a></p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-04-28-raining</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://allotmentandy.github.io/blog/2020-04-28-raining" />
    <title>Rainy Day - Thoughts about Debian</title>
    <published>2020-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Allotment Andy</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">8.15am in bed, it is raining, wondering what to do today.

I have been using Debian Linux for years, I guess about version 5. Recently I
found the 4.9 kernel caused the computer to lock / freeze completely, with an
upgrade to the 4.19 kernel even worse.......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>8.15am in bed, it is raining, wondering what to do today.</p>

<p>I have been using Debian Linux for years, I guess about version 5. Recently I
found the 4.9 kernel caused the computer to lock / freeze completely, with an
upgrade to the 4.19 kernel even worse. So I backed up my machine and installed
Debian testing! This fixed the freezing issue and the computer has not crashed
in weeks.</p>

<h2>Today i learnt</h2>

<p>to show all installed apps in debian with a description</p>

<pre><code>dpkg-query -l
</code></pre>

<h2>Jigsaw</h2>

<p>Building this website using the jigsaw static site, but as default the search
only worked for the _posts pages, so i added a new collection to the search
json and merged them together. now you can search all the pages. Must look
into the Fuse.js that is making it.</p>

<h3>Update - 23.05pm -</h3>

<p>Have had a good day, learning Markdown, Tailwind CSS, Jigsaw Static Site
development. Found some good docs on the internet to help me learn all this.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
    </feed>
